Austin Evans

Denver, CO 80222 | 720-207-7151 | austin.dv.evans@gmail.com Github.com/Austin-dv-Evans | Medium.com/@austin.dv.evans | AustinEvansApp on GooglePlay

SOFTWARE ENGINEER

Experienced in Ruby on Rails, JavaScript based programming and Android Development with a background in Entertainment Media Management. Possess strong skills in interpersonal communication, team management and brand strategy that helps tech companies drive productivity and success. Here to progress the future of tech with creativity and hard work.

CERTIFICATES

<u>Programming Hub</u>: Android Development, CSS, Dart, HTML, Javascript, Javascript Advanced, Kotlin, Node JS, React Development, Ruby.

Mimo: Learn to Code and Learn to Code for Android Apps.

TECHNICAL PROJECTS

Moment - Kotlin | Java | Android Studio

Instantly start recording video on your phone with voice activation. "Moments" would save to "My Moments Gallery".

- Implemented Speech Recognition to invoke native device media.
- Utilized foreground operations, broadcast receivers and notification services for diverse access of functionalities.
- Integrated, Google's latest camera api, Camera X.
- Created and published a full functioning android application in just over two and a half weeks.
 Github Youtube

myAgent - React | Ruby on Rails

A mobile application designed for musicians to eliminate the need for a booking agent.

- Full Authentication with JWT and BCrypt allowing users to sign up or login.
- Managed State and Props throughout Components for the user to create and manage their list of gigs.
- Developed models and created validated relationships and locked the application down with private routes.
- Built a smooth React application that musicians could benefit from in less than four days Github Youtube

The Stainerator - Javascript | Ruby on Rails

A mobile application designed to entertain the mindless.

- Seeded and organized a sqlite3 database, users could read and create seeds.
- Fetch chains accessed sections of the database then functions were performed on the results.
- Designed multiple user interfaces where the user could view the database and submit form entries.
- Crafted an easy to use and entertaining application in less than four days.
 Github Youtube

EXPERIENCE

GFDM Denver, Colorado
Owner and CEO 08/2015 - Present

- Started and ran a personal passion project, impacting Denver's electronic music scene.
- Focused on a niche, built a following, leading to event production, artist management and booking.

AmbliDenver, ColoradoDistrict Manager05/2018 - 03/2020

- Lead a management team through expanding from two restaurants to four restaurants and a music venue.
- Oversaw daily operations and finances for all properties, hired employees and developed a training manual.

EDUCATION

Flatiron SchoolFull Stack Web Development, Ruby on Rails and JavaScript program

Denver, Colorado

05/ 2020 - 09/2020

University of Colorado, Denver

Bachelor's Degree, Music Entertainment Industry Studies

Denver, Colorado

02/2015